<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Department of the Interior (DOI), National Park Service (NPS), Land Resources Division (LRD), Intermountain Land Resources Program Center </origin><pubdate>20220307 </pubdate><title>Grand Teton National Park Tract and Boundary Data </title><edition>20220307 </edition><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Lakewood, CO </pubplace><publish>National Park Service Land Resources Division </publish></pubinfo><onlink>http://nrdata.nps.gov/programs/Lands/grte_tracts.zip </onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>These ESRI shape files are of National Park Service tract and boundary data that was created by the Land Resources Division. Tracts are numbered and created by the regional cartographic staff at the Land Resources Program Centers and are associated to the Land Status Maps. This data should be used to display properties that NPS owns and properties that NPS may have some type of interest such as scenic easements or right of ways.</abstract><purpose>This data is intended to keep a record of ownership information. Tracts can represent several types of interest like fee and scenic easement, and can be under several types of ownership like NPS owned, private, other federal, state or county. This data set provides accurate and reliable ownership data for park management and acquisition priorities.</purpose></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>19290226</begdate><enddate>20220307 </enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><current>Beginning date is the first recorded conveyance date. Ending date is set to the last day the data set was updated. </current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-110.948417</westbc><eastbc>-110.422732</eastbc><northbc>44.084006</northbc><southbc>43.537923</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>Boundaries</themekey><themekey>Planning Cadastre</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>None</themekt><themekey>Boundary</themekey><themekey>Ownership</themekey><themekey>Parcels</themekey><themekey>Tracts</themekey><themekey>LRDCAB</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>National Park Service Theme Category Thesaurus</themekt></theme><place><placekt>None</placekt><placekey>United States</placekey><placekey>National Park Service</placekey><placekey>Grand Teton National Park</placekey><placekey>Intermountain</placekey><placekey>Wyoming</placekey></place><place><placekt>National Park System Unit Code Thesaurus</placekt><placekey>GRTE</placekey></place><place><placekt>National Park System Unit Name Thesaurus</placekt><placekey>Grand Teton National Park</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None </accconst><useconst>NPS Director's Order #25 states: "Land status maps will be prepared to identify the ownership of the lands within the authorized boundaries of the park unit. These maps, showing ownership and acreage, are the 'official record' of the acreage of Federal and non-federal lands within the park boundaries. While these maps are the official record of the lands and acreage within the unit's authorized boundaries, they are not of survey quality and not intended to be used for survey purposes." As such this data is intended for use as a tool for GIS analysis. It is in no way intended for engineering or legal purposes. The data accuracy is checked against best available sources which may be dated and vary by location. NPS assumes no liability for use of this data. The boundary polygons LRD creates represent the current legislated boundary of a given NPS unit. NPS does not necessarily have full fee ownership or hold another interest (easement, right of way, etc...) in all parcels contained within this boundary. Equivalently NPS may own or have an interest in parcels outside the legislated boundary of a given unit. In order to obtain complete information about current NPS interests both inside and outside the units legislated boundary, the tracts file created by LRD should be used in conjunction with this boundary file created by LRD.</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NPS - Land Resources Division, Intermountain Region </cntorg><cntper>Scott Thompson-Buchanan</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Cartographer </cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>12795 W. Alameda Pkwy. </address><city>Lakewood </city><state>CO </state><postal>80521 </postal><country>USA </country></cntaddr><cntvoice>303-969-2419 </cntvoice><cntfax>303-969-2499</cntfax><cntemail>scott_thompson-buchanan@nps.gov </cntemail><hours>6:30am-3:00pm M-F Mountain </hours></cntinfo></ptcontac><datacred>Department of the Interior (DOI), National Park Service (NPS), Land Resources Division (LRD), Intermountain Land Resources Program Center </datacred><crossref><citeinfo><origin>Department of the Interior (DOI), National Park Service (NPS), Land Resources Division (LRD), Intermountain Land Resources Program Center </origin><pubdate>20180330</pubdate><title>Metadata for Grand Teton National Park Tract and Boundary Data</title><onlink>http://nrdata.nps.gov/programs/lands/grte_metadata.xml</onlink></citeinfo></crossref></idinfo><dataqual><logic>Link and node polygon topology is created using AutoCAD Cilvil 3D 2018. The data is then exported to ESRI shape file format and reprojected from it's native AutoCAD coordinate system to NAD83 generic latitude and longitude, LL83.</logic><complete>Information contained in LRD's land ownership databases is updated nightly however tract polygons are posted to the NPS Data Store on a monthly basis. Users can ensure parcel polygons have up to date ownership attribution after the publication date by contacting your regional LRD office or downloading the Current_Tract_Ownership_Data file located on the NPS Data Store (http://science.nature.nps.gov/nrdata/) in a dBase format. Please contact the data originator with any suggested corrections and updates. LRD's boundary polygons represent the current legislated boundary of a given NPS unit. NPS does not necessarily have full fee ownership or hold another interest (easement, right of way, etc...) in all parcels contained within this boundary. Equivalently NPS may own or have an interest in parcels outside the legislated boundary of a given unit. In order to obtain complete information about current NPS interests both inside and outside the units legislated boundary, LRD's tracts files should also be downloaded and used in conjunction with LRD's boundary files. </complete><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>National Park Service - Land Resources Division </origin><pubdate>20220307 </pubdate><title>Legal Descriptions </title><edition>N/A </edition><geoform>document - legal description </geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Intermountain Land Resources Program Center </pubplace><publish>Land Resources Division </publish></pubinfo><othercit>None </othercit></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>1 </srcscale><typesrc>MANDATORY</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>19290226 </begdate><enddate>20220307 </enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><srccurr>Beginning Date represents first conveyed date. Ending date is when the data was last updated. </srccurr></srctime><srccitea>Legal Descriptions </srccitea><srccontr>tract and boundary geometry, Tract_id, Alpha </srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>National Park Service - Land Resources Division </origin><pubdate>20220307 </pubdate><title>Deeds </title><edition>N/A </edition><geoform>document - deed </geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Intermountain Land Resources Program Center </pubplace><publish>Land Resources Division </publish></pubinfo><othercit>None </othercit></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>1 </srcscale><typesrc>MANDATORY</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>19290226</begdate><enddate>20220307 </enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><srccurr>Beginning Date represents first conveyed date. Ending date is when the data was last updated. </srccurr></srctime><srccitea>deeds </srccitea><srccontr>tract and boundary geometry, Tract_id, Alpha </srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>National Park Service - Land Resources Division </origin><pubdate>20220307 </pubdate><title>Segment Maps </title><edition>N/A </edition><geoform>map - segment map </geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Intermountain Land Resources Program Center </pubplace><publish>Land Resources Division </publish></pubinfo><othercit>None </othercit></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>1200 - 63360 </srcscale><typesrc>MANDATORY</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>19290226</begdate><enddate>20220307 </enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><srccurr>Beginning Date represents first conveyed date. Ending date is when the data was last updated. </srccurr></srctime><srccitea>segment maps </srccitea><srccontr>tract and boundary geometry, Tract_id, Alpha </srccontr></srcinfo><procstep><procdesc>PLSS for Teton county was downloaded from the BLM's state site (http://www.blm.gov/wy/st/en/resources/public_room/gis/datagis/county/gcdb.html) in coverage format on 20080602. The AutoCAD Map IMPORT command used to import these coverages. This information was used as a base to geo-reference the boundary and tracts for GRTE. Not all of GRTE has been surveyed, so projected sections were created (i.e, around Jackson Lake). Tracts that were described by aliquot part descriptions were created making copies of this line work. For those tracts described by bearing and distance descriptions, this PLSS layer was also used as points-of-beginning and a basis for ground to grid scale and rotation transformations. The horizontal accuracy of the surveyed townships for GRTE is NOT consistent. Therefore, the PLSS line work was not used in these cases. Used Watershed boundary ArcInfo coverage from the University of Wyoming's Geographic Information Science Center (http://www.wygisc.uwyo.edu/) to delineate hydrographic boundaries. This dataset meets federal standards for delineation of hydrologic unit boundaries. Local experts (Frank Jackson of the USFS and Paul Caffrey of UWyo) suggested that I use this boundary rather than the USGS National Hydrography Dataset (NHD) data because of their confidence in this dataset. It was downloaded on 20080409. This dataset defined the hydrographic boundaries for tracts 10-120 and 11-115. For those tracts that follow the centerline of a road (e.g., Moose-Wilson Road)or the bank or main thread of a watercourse (Snake and Gros Ventre Rivers), 2006 NAIP ortho-photography was on-screen digitized to create boundaries. Tracts 06-127 &amp; 06-127A were entered using COGO from the description included with the grant of easement. The AutoCAD Project was projected to Wyoming State Plane, Zone West, NAD83, US Foot. The AutoCAD line work is imported, edited, attributed, approved, and a link and node topology is developed both for the tract and boundary data layers according to the procedures described in the Land Acquisition Procedures Manual Chapter 5. The entire unit is created in a geographically contiguous model space and separate layouts representing each individual segment map are created. The tract and boundary data is then reprojected to North American Datum 1983 generic latitude &amp; longitude and exported from AutoCAD to an ArcView shape file format in a single step.</procdesc><srcused>withheld</srcused><srcused>withheld</srcused><srcused>withheld</srcused><srcused>withheld</srcused><srcused>withheld</srcused><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NPS Land Resources Division, WASO-Fort Collins </cntorg><cntper>Scott Thompson-Buchanan</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Cartographer </cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>12795 W. Alameda Pkwy. </address><city>Lakewood </city><state>CO </state><postal>80228 </postal><country>US</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>303-969-2419 </cntvoice><cntfax>303-969-2419 </cntfax><cntemail>scott_thompson-buchanan@nps.gov </cntemail><hours>6:30am-3:00pm M-F Mountain </hours></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>03072022 Attribution change for Tract 02-182. Ownership status changed from PRIV to FEE 03072022 Attribution update for Tract 02-183. Ownership status changed from PRIV to FEE in 2019 and never updated into Tractsnet</procdesc><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Department of the Interior (DOI), National Park Service (NPS), Land Resources Division (LRD), Intermountain Land Resources Program Center </cntorg><cntper>Jeremy Roth</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Cartographer</cntpos></cntinfo></proccont></procstep></lineage></dataqual><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>grte_tracts.dbf </enttypl><enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table </enttypd><enttypds>None </enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>Alpha </attrlabl><attrdef>Provides the unit identification code. </attrdef><attrdefs>"Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS)", revised 2017. </attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Attributes were created according to the National Park Service, Washington Land Resources Division, Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS) revised 2017. </udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Tract_id </attrlabl><attrdef>Provides the tract identification number. </attrdef><attrdefs>"Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS)", revised 2017. </attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Attributes were created according to the National Park Service, Washington Land Resources Division, Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS) revised 2017. </udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Status </attrlabl><attrdef>Defines if an interest is a parcel is NPS owned, held by another Federal agency or a non-Federal party. </attrdef><attrdefs>"Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS)", revised 2017. </attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Attributes were created according to the National Park Service, Washington Land Resources Division, Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS) revised 2017. </udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Estate </attrlabl><attrdef>Expresses the degree, nature, quality, or extent of an interest NPS has acquired. </attrdef><attrdefs>"Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS)", revised 2017. </attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Attributes were created according to the National Park Service, Washington Land Resources Division, Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS) revised 2017. </udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Areatract </attrlabl><attrdef>A field used to relate each parcel to the Current_Tract_Ownership_Data.dbf file located on the NPS Data Store. </attrdef><attrdefs>"Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS)", revised 2017. </attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Attributes were created according to the National Park Service, Washington Land Resources Division, Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS) revised 2017. </udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed><overview><eaover>Attributes were created according to the National Park Service, Land Resources Division, Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS).</eaover><eadetcit>"Land Acquisition Procedures (LAPS)", Mapping Standards - Chapter 5, revised 2017. </eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NPS - Land Resources Division, WASO-FC </cntorg><cntper>Roger Johnson </cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Chief Cartographer </cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>301 South Howes Street Suite 208 </address><city>Fort Collins </city><state>CO </state><postal>80522 </postal><country>US</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>970-484-6428 </cntvoice><cntfax>970-484-6432 </cntfax><cntemail>roger_m_johnson@nps.gov </cntemail><hours>7:00am-5:30pm Mountain Monday-Thursday </hours></cntinfo></distrib><distliab>Property ownership data is compiled from deeds, plats, surveys, and other source data. These are not engineering quality drawings and should be used for administrative purposes only. The National Park Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The related graphics are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data; it is not appropriate to use the related graphics as data. The National Park Service gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from an NPS server and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the National Park Service, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on another system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>ESRI Shapefile </formname></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>http://nrdata.nps.gov/programs/Lands/grte_tracts.zip </networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt></digtopt></digform><fees>None </fees></stdorder></distinfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NPS - Land Resources Division, WASO-FC </cntorg><cntper>Roger Johnson </cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Chief Cartographer </cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>301 South Howes Street Suite 208 </address><city>Fort Collins </city><state>CO </state><postal>80522 </postal><country>US</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>970-484-6428 </cntvoice><cntfax>970-484-6432 </cntfax><cntemail>roger_m_johnson@nps.gov </cntemail><hours>7:00am-5:30pm Mountain Monday-Thursday </hours></cntinfo></distrib><distliab>Property ownership data is compiled from deeds, plats, surveys, and other source data. These are not engineering quality drawings and should be used for administrative purposes only. The National Park Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The related graphics are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data; it is not appropriate to use the related graphics as data. The National Park Service gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from an NPS server and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the National Park Service, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on another system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data.</distliab><custom>
To get a hard copy plot, contact Land Resources Program
Center for replacement costs and turnaround times.
</custom></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20220407</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NPS Land Resources Division, WASO-Fort Collins </cntorg><cntper>Scott Thompson-Buchanan</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Cartographer </cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>12795 W. Alameda Pkwy. </address><city>Lakewood </city><state>CO </state><postal>80521 </postal><country>US</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>303-969-2419 </cntvoice><cntfax>303-969-2499 </cntfax><cntemail>scott_thompson-buchanan@nps.gov </cntemail><hours>6:30am-3:00pm M-F Mountain </hours></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc></metainfo></metadata>
